## **Scott Rubin**

scottrubin@gmail.com | 646-637-6377 | Portfolio: https://www.8cott.com | https://www.linkedin.com/in/srubin

#### **SOFTWARE ENGINEER**

Creative Software Engineer with excellent problem-solving abilities and technical communication skills, with extensive experience developing websites and applications to enhance a successful real estate business. Blending a diverse entrepreneurial background with technical skills to make a significant impact in a software engineering role.

#### **SKILLS PROFILE**

**Programming & Web Technologies:** JavaScript, Python, TypeScript, Swift, HTML, CSS, React, Redux, Flask, Django, Node.js, Express, Prompt Engineering, OpenAI, ChatGPT

Databases & Cloud Services: MongoDB, PostgreSQL, AWS, Vercel, Heroku

**Security & Development Tools:** IAM, Multi-factor Authentication, Github, VSCode, XCode, Jupyter Notebooks **Business Skills:** Entrepreneurship, Sales, Negotiation, Communication, Marketing, Presentations, Public Speaking

#### **PROJECTS**

# GPT Fitness | Website | Github (Client/Server)

October 2023

- Created an App that uses OpenAl's GPT API to create custom Fitness & Diet plans
- Backend built with Flask, Python, Postgresql. Frontend built with React, Vite, Axios.

# Listings App | Link | Github (Client/Server)

July 2023

- Created a Full Stack MERN application to create, read, update and delete real estate listings.
- Used Node, Express, MongoDB, Vite, and React with full CRUD functionality.

## Closing Costs Calculator | Link | Github

July 2023

Created an app in Vite/React to calculate New York City real estate closing costs.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Compass New York, NY April 2018 – Present

Licensed Associate Real Estate Broker & Software Developer

### **Software Development and Digital Marketing:**

- **Designed and Developed Real Estate Websites**: Implemented branding and marketing strategies, resulting in a 42% increase in qualified leads. Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript.
- **Built Mortgage & Closing Costs Calculator App**: Developed a user-friendly application using React, aiding buyers and sellers in financial calculations.
- **Participation in Compass Hackathon**: Created innovative tools leveraging OpenAI/ChatGPT, Python, and JavaScript to create social media content.
- **Digital Marketing Initiatives**: Spearheaded ad campaigns across OTT, Google Ads/YouTube, Facebook, Instagram, and MailChimp; enhanced online presence and branding.

## **Real Estate Expertise and Client Engagement:**

- **Property Marketing**: Developed effective marketing strategies for properties for sale and rent, including creating compelling PowerPoint presentations for prospective buyers and sellers.
- **Content Creation**: Initiated and hosted a weekly Real Estate podcast on Buzzsprout; wrote and directed short commercials for digital marketing.
- **Client Relationship Management**: Utilized Compass CRM and Salesforce for efficient client management and action plan execution.

# **Scott Rubin**

• **Market Analysis**: Compiled and analyzed Comparable Market Analyses using Excel and Google Sheets to accurately value properties.

### Town Residential New York, NY

September 2016 - April 2018

Licensed Associate Real Estate Broker

- Recruited, managed, and mentored a team of 10 agents and day-to-day activities.
- Presented at public speaking engagements to educate prospective clients about the business and to network.
- Created agent branding website using Wordpress and Elementor.

### Douglas Elliman New York, NY

September 2012 - September 2016

Licensed Associate Real Estate Broker

- Received the Douglas Elliman Gold Award for GCI in both 2014 and 2015.
- Managed a team of up to five agents to help with career development and increase the overall GCI of our team.
- Consulted on the development on the front-end of the new company web application for real estate listings.

### Mark David & Company New York, NY

January 2005 – September 2012

Licensed Associate Real Estate Broker

- Developed and conducted sales training based on the Sandler Selling System.
- Received award for top Hybrid Agent (Sales/Leasing) 2006.
- Managed a team of 5 agents who closed 94 transactions in the 2010 calendar year, including both sales and rentals.
- Consulted on several software development projects to implement new back-end and front-end websites and database applications for the company's website for real estate listings.

#### **EDUCATION**

### **New York University (NYU)**

New York, NY

Software Development Professional Certificate

**Courses:** JavaScript, Python, Object Oriented Programming, REST, CRUD, Data Structures, Algorithms, Big O, HTML & Web Accessibility, CSS & CSS Frameworks, UX & UI Design, Front-End Development, Back-End Development & APIs, SQL & Data Modeling, React & Redux, Cybersecurity.

Five Towns College Dix Hills, NY

Music Performance & Composition